Andrey Turbov

Software Engineer | DevOps | SRE 6 years

Contact

LinkedIn: Andrey Turbov E-mail: unsip@tuta.io Phone: +995 591812617

Github: https://github.com/unsip

Software and operations engineer with a several years of SRE expertise. I possess extensive experience across entire production lifecycle and understand wide range of issues regarding backend/frontend development, system administration, QA, operations, incident management and customer perspectives. My experience in an international environment combined with fluent English enables me to get along with foreign co-workers and customers quickly. Self-education is of the highest value for me, which I am always striving for. I appreciate scientific endeavors and enjoy exploring world of abstract ideas. I aim to further develop my skills in software engineering, architecture design and distributed systems. My primary career goal is to acquire expertise in technologically advanced domains with a focus on reliability and social impact such as finance, healthcare, telecommunications, automotive, education, hardware, OS development and Research & Development (R&D) departments.

Employment

Freelance (Cmakify, GatewayFM)

Software Engineer

Jul 2023 — Present Tbilisi

- Developed initial platform prototype for automatic conversion/generation of CMake files with Django/DRF
 - Collected customer projects Make files issues to resolve reduce build system maintainance load
 - Integrated CMake files parser into Django application to enchance customer current build techniques
- Django/DRF/ReactJS service for automated crypto infrastructure deployment to various cloud providers:
 - Implementation of new features and bug reduction via legacy code refactoring
 - Introduced TDD and existing code coverage with pytest + CI/CD pipelines configuration
 - Monitoring alerts configuration catching critical application issues such as stale deployments, queues overflow, etc.

JettyCloud (RingCentral)

Release Engineer

Dec 2022 — Apr 2023

- Tbilisi
- Design and maintain internal custom *Python* toolchain for mass services release
- \bullet Optimization of existing and decommission of redundant instances to cut company operation costs by 15%
- Carry out release preparation cycle including:
 - Deployment of minor (120-150 services) and major (more than 150 services) releases of RC distributed system
 - Tracing and resolving issues occurred during QA regression cycles
 - Bug reporting and discussion with developers on possible solutions, suggesting possible patches

Apr 2022 — Dec 2022

Tbilisi

Site Reliability Engineer

- Delivery and configuration on high-load microservice production environment with over 30000 servers and instances
- Subsystems support handover from other teams with comprehensive review and presentation for peers
- Tracing and resolving service critical routing issues and telecommunication failures with further RCA
- Collaborated closely with international customers, operations and development teams to achieve 99.999% system reliability
- Deployment processes automation with *Python* toolset

Teknavo (Bloomberg)

DevOps Engineer

Dec 2021 — Apr 2022 St. Petersburg

- Internal Bloomberg CI/CD infrastructure improvement to speed up build and release process
- Build and unit/integration tests automation with Python, CMake, GTest and pytest
- C++ codebase tests coverage and bugfixing

T-Systems (Deutsche Telekom)

Software Developer

• Design new system architecture for *Python Django* RPA platform with UML

- Refactoring of a legacy Django/DRF/Celery/Flask backend according to new system design
- \bullet Transition from RPC (RPyC) protocol to plain REST API to simplify backend-agent communication
- Implemented multiprocessing Python RPA agent-side for easy bots management and concurrent execution
- ReactJS frontend development and improvements following strict company UI standards
- Introduced TDD practice for both frontend and backend:
 - Frontend unit-test configuration and coverage using Jest and Enzyme
 - Backend and agent unit-testing with pytest, factory_boy for data mocking, pytest-cov for coverage metrics
 - Organized knowledge sharing sessions on how to properly unit-test components using pytest
 - Paired programming sessions with colleagues to help with TDD adoption

DevOps Engineer

Jul 2018 — Jan 2020 St. Petersburg

- Monthly presentations on international on-site meetings in a large scale project of more than 200 coworkers
- Support for international DEV, QA and SRE teams during full software development lifecycle
- Orchestration solution design and development using Puppet and Puppet Bolt
- Migration of CI/CD pipelines from Jenkins to GitLab CI
- Implementation of internal services and utilities such as:
 - Django/DRF/ReactJS dashboard web service for project environments
 - Flask service for generating delivery instructions for production OPS
 - Python CLI utility for complex application configuration management

Education

2014 - 2016	Saint Petersburg State University of Aerospace Instrumentation, Department of Computer Science
2013 - 2014	Peter the Great Saint-Petersburg Polytechnic University, Department of Physics and Astronomy

Used Tools

Programming languages: Python, C++(11/14/17), JavaScript (ES6), Elixir

Frameworks: Django, Django REST Framework (DRF), Flask, Celery, RPyC, ReactJS

Development utilities: Git, Bash, core *nix utilities, rpm, dpkg, Sphinx

Operating systems: Linux (RHEL, Debian, Arch, Gentoo, Exherbo), Windows

Build systems and CI/CD: Make, Ninja, CMake, Gitlab CI, Jenkins

Cloud and Virtualization: Docker, k8s/Spinnaker, AWS, Vagrant, VirtualBox, VMware

Infrastructure orchestration: Ansible, Puppet, Puppet Bolt, Terraform

Monitoring: ELK stack, Grafana, Prometheus, Zabbix

Databases: PostgreSQL, OracleDB, Amazon RDS

Other

Languages: advanced English, native Russian

Achievements: participated in student physics and astronomy conferences/competitions, completed MIT GSL program on start-up creation from scratch and pitch for venture fund

Hobbies: programming, Exherbo Linux distribution maintainance, philosophy and humanity studies, digital art, spider keeping

Jan 2020 — Dec 2021 St. Petersburg